ALEXANDER BURR

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Email alex@alexburr.com LinkedIn alexanderburr Phone (585) 305-5872 GitHub alexburr Web www.alexburr.com

JSFiddle alexburr

Software developer with over 25 years of experience in all phases of the software life cycle. A passion for creating a culture of design thinking and user experience focus. Enjoys opportunities to develop solutions with new technologies and learn new domains, and strives to foster sharing and mentorship between development colleagues. Experienced in Agile development with Scrum, works with a continuous integration mindset, pays attention to details, and strives to establish a standard of quality and improvement in all areas of work.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer, Mindex — Rochester, NY

May 2021-present

- SOW position for an industry-leading HRIS services provider, supporting the retirement division with full-stack development contributing to HRIS
 solutions. Provided new features and updates for legal and compliance mandates, as well as new business opportunities.
- Recent projects included: syncing of 401(k) deferrals for participants enrolled in multiple plans, client auto-enrollment automation, and participant rollover/withdrawal history web view.
- Senior software position duties included accountability for production incident support, business UAT support, and working closely with solution leads, as well as mentoring and guiding other team members.
- Developed new features for internal user systems in a microservice architecture on Java Spring Boot Framework, added production support queries and reports utilizing PL/SQL and Python, and built automated tests on Robot Framework.
- Updated existing and developed new web user interfaces for end-user retirement fund management, in a shared SPA platform utilizing AngularJS and React.

Software Engineer, Pharos Systems International — Rochester, NY

June 2012-April 2021

- Full-stack development of cloud print management solution and secure print solution
- Included user interface design, .Net MVC web service development with C\$ and Razor, and ASP.NET Core Web API services
- · Web UI development with jQuery, Kendo UI, React, Angular, and custom proprietary front-end frameworks

Lead Web Developer, University of Rochester Medical Center — Rochester, NY

July 2010-June 2012

- Developed intranet web applications with ASP.Net and SharePoint
- Designed web user interfaces for internal business applications
- Oversaw publishing of news content and employee recognition announcements

Senior Web Developer, University of Rochester Medical Center — Rochester, NY

September 2007-June 2010

- Developed patient-facing web content for multiple hospital departments & centers
- Developed Health Encyclopedia using ColdFusion

Production Manager, Cazbah — Rochester, NY

September 2004-September 2007

Web Developer, Element K - Rochester, NY

October 2003-December 2003

Software Engineer, AHT — Rochester, NY

June 2000-July 2002

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

Languages

C#, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL

Databases

Oracle (PL/SQL), SQL Server (T-SQL), NoSQL (MongoDB), MySQL

Frameworks and templating

Spring Boot, React, Angular JS, ASP.Net MVC, Web API, Spring, Razor, Nancy, Smarty, Codelgniter, ColdFusion

Unit testing

xUnit.net, Moq, Jest, jUnit, Mockito

Content management systems

Umbraco, WordPress, Textpattern, and Cascade Server

Wireframing and design

Figma, Gliffy, Axure RP, Adobe Photoshop, Visio, Balsamiq

Source code management

Git, Mercurial, Subversion, TFS

Environments

Windows/IIS/OpenShift and Linux/Apache, AWS

Project concepts

Life cycle methodology, needs assessment and usability, information architecture, content strategy, SEO and conversion, and analytics

Soft skills

Resourceful, experienced troubleshooting, providing documentation and communication skills

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, May 2000

REFERENCES

Available upon request.